Noël Macé

Senior Web Developer

Experience: 14 years

My passionate and inquiring nature lead me to a constant quest for new technical, intellectual, and human challenges.

This brought me to a wide variety of roles, from which I gained diverse knowledge and experience (software development and architecture, sysadmin and netadmin, teaching and pedagogy, management, communication, etc.).

Web development — and more specifically the web platform, dev tools et standards — is my main focus since 2014, and a long-time passion.

Réseaux

in

/in/noelmdev



@nlm-pro



noelmace.com

Languages

English: advanced (C1/C2)

French: native & advanced

Spanish: basics (A2)



expertise

Web Architecture & Development

- Holistic and objective mastery of Web development principles and fundamentals (Web Components, Web APIs, PWAs, PRPL, a11y, performance, etc.)
- Fluent in a wide variety of frameworks and libraries (Lit, Open WC, Angular, React, Vue, Redux, Gatsby, 11ty, etc.)
- Advanced expertise in Angular, Angular CLI & Nrwl/Nx (OSS contributor from 2016 to 2018, then regular monitoring)
- Wrote a thorough book about modern web development fundamentals (published in french by ENI editions in 2021)
- Fullstack and DevOps proficiencies (REST, ORM, CI/CD, SGBD, Docker, PaaS, Node.js, Python, Java, etc.)



guiding thread

Pedagogy

- Mentoring and teaching are the backbone of my whole career
- Estensive and wide experience as an independant instructor, teacher, educational designer and teaching manager, having led large teams in both instructionnal and R&D environments



motivations

Sharing & Research

- Strong and long-standing interest for Open Source and the free culture mouvement in general
- Created and gave numerous workshops et lectures
- Love documentation, typing et testing and master the related tools and good practices

Schedule an interview on



calendly.com/noelmace

Experience



freelance

Since jan. 2020

CONSULTANT & TRAINER

Web Development & Architecture



Blindnet start-up

From feb. 2022 to oct. 2022

VP, TECHNOLOGY & PEDAGOGY

- Leading Web, Java, and Scala development.
- Customer Support & Technical Documentation maintenance.
- Privacy Advocacy.



ENI Editions book publisher

From march 2020 to march 2021

AUTHOR

- Wrote a thorough book bringing a new perspective on Modern Web Development fundamentals (608 pages).
- Developed a wide variety of examples, tests, and automation tools (16500 lines of code).
- Created Open Source libraries, tools, scripts, and projects as proof of concepts and illustrations.



Bonitasoft

Open Source Software Editor (BPM)

From apr. 2019 to oct. 2019

DEVELOPER ADVOCATE, WEB

- **DevX, performance, and modernization**: lead and contribute to the migration from *AngularJS* to *Web Components*.
- Set up strategies and tools to facilitate content creation and technical events management (via Gatsby, Netlify CMS & GitHub).



SFEIR ESN, 500 employés

From june 2018 to apr. 2019

DEVELOPER ADVOCATE / WEB ARCHITECT

- **Twofold mission**: technical expertise (3d/w) and developer advocacy.
- Improved the stability and maintainability of an Angular,
 NgRx et Preact application as a technical leader for "la Société Générale".
- Supervision and training of a team of 30 Angular developers (in both Paris & Hong Kong) for the BNP Paribas company.
- Audit and performance improvement of several Progressive Web Apps (in VanillaJS, React, Vue, Angular), migrations from AngularJS to Angular, defined the architecture for several new Web Apps, etc.

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR, JAVASCRIPT / WEB APP ARCHITECT

- Architecture & Technical Direction for 8 front-end JavaScript projects (AngularJS, JQuery, PHP et Node.js), leading 3 teams of 12 developers.
- Defining the reference web front-end web architecture for Sedona and the *Harmonie Mutuelle* group.
- **Modernisation** of Web technologies usages for the whole groupe (Sedona, West, RedShift et Inadeo brands).
- (From dec. 2016) Lead Angular Architect, Saint Gobain:
 Defining and maintaining transversal guidelines and tooling for 3 projects, leading 6 teams (30 developers).

Sedona *ESN, 100 employés*



From dec. 2015 to may 2018

LEAD DEVELOPER ANGULARIS

Development of the account management and Euromillions "widgets" with **AngularJS 1.4 and ES2015** for the fdj.fr portal, leading a team of 8 developers.

Française des Jeux

From june 2015 to nov. 2015



TRAINER, CONSULTANT

- 38 courses delivered both on-line and face-to-face.
- **3 applications** Java (Spring, Struts, Hibernate) & Android developed.

freelance

From mai 2011 to nov. 2015



DIRECTOR OF UNIX TEACHING

- Hiring and training 70 teachers hired for Linux, Apple & Sécurité education on the 30 sites of the group.
- Defining, writing, and managing **7 educational units**.

Supinfo

International University

From june 2010 to apr. 2011



TEACHER / TRAINER

Teaching 12 educational units on 18 sites, in 3 different countries.

Supinfo

From oct. 2009 to juin 2010



Creations

28 Lectures & Workshops

- Web Applications Architecture
- Web Performance
- Soft Skills
- Corporate Strategy
- Web Development Frameworks & Libraries
- IT History

13 Podcasts

- Soft Skills
- Lead Development
- Workplace Wellness

20+ Publications

- Reference Book
- Blogs
- White Papers
- Training Manuals
- Technical & Organizational Documentations
- Copywriting

∞ Open Source projects

- CLIs
- Static Site Generators
- Framework and Libraries for Web Development
- Experiments, Technical Demonstrations, Proofs of Concepts...

Hobbies & Interests

- Free Culture, Open Source & Ethical Source
- Pedagogy and Science Popularization
- Tabletop Roleplay & Board Games
- Mathematics & Theorical Physics
- Natural, Social & Cognitive Sciences
- Legos, Model Creation & Puzzles

Education

- 2010 : Master of IT Engineering, Supinfo International University
- 2007: Associate Degree in Applied Mathematics for Social Science, Toulouse Jean Jaurès University